<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://curiousprogrammer.net/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Curious (Clojure) Programmer</title><link>http://curiousprogrammer.net/</link><description>Simplicity matters</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 07:42:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>http://curiousprogrammer.net/posts-output/2022-01-12-moving-to-cryogen</guid><link>http://curiousprogrammer.net/posts-output/2022-01-12-moving-to-cryogen</link><title>Moving My Blog to Cryogen and Cloudflare Pages</title><description>The Wordpress problemI wanted to migrate away from the existing Wordpress-based hosting for
my curiosprogrammer.net blog
for a long time yet I have not found time to do that until now.
Today, I’m finally moving towards much simpler approach using
Cryogen as the underlying blog engine.CryogenCryogen is a simple blog engine written in Clojure.
It’s used by a number of people in Clojure community, including Sean Corfield and Jakub Holy.I think it will well serve my needs
and I hope that the friction for publishing posts
(and the frustrations caused by Wordpress editor)
is going to diminish.AsciiDocI’ve found a couple of AsciiDoc-related links in
Jakub Holy’s article
and decided to give it a try.
The promise is that, unlike Markdown, it’s standardized, extensible and has richer formatting options.See:Why You Shouldn’t Use “Markdown” for DocumentationCompare AsciiDoc to MarkdownAsciiDoc Syntax Quick Reference</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://curiousprogrammer.net/posts-output/2017-02-08-random-excepts-from-brno-clojure-meetup</guid><link>http://curiousprogrammer.net/posts-output/2017-02-08-random-excepts-from-brno-clojure-meetup</link><title>Random excerpts from Brno Clojure meetup</title><description>Meetup notesLast week, I was quite happy to attend (:brno Clojure) meetup.
There were only five people including me.
Nevertheless, we had a great time and covered a lot of topics.
There was no main theme, just live free and spontaneous discussion about our experience with Clojure.
We discussed following topics:server-side template ducteasy-to-use template for getting started with Clojure web applicationshow is it different from chestnut?liskasysKarel Miarka’s own projectUses DatomicEmacs/Spacemacs vs.
CursiveSpacemacs has lots of preconfigured plugins =&gt; easier to use than plain EmacsKorma SQLmacro magicconsider using something else (Honey SQL, plain clojure.java.jdbc, …​)Check https://yogthos.net/posts/2016-02-22-LuminusEmbracingHugSQL.html“Specs” for re-frame application state dbIt can be better to not enforce using spec for app-db because the additional value is not so high and it can lead to tedious updates of spec whenever you add something to app-dbUsefulness of namespaced keywordsavoid conflicts: same keywords in different namespacesPitfalls of debugging CLJSunclear error messageshard to find root causeLogginglog whole Clojure data structure instead of standard log lines?you can then process logs with clojure (search, filter, …​)Using Ansible for automatic deploymentComponent reloaded workflowfigwheel-like experience on backendFigwheelre-load on save vs.
reload explicitly (triggered by keyboard shortcut)explicit reload gives us a better controlIdeas for next meetupsApplications / System showcasesdemonstrate the apps we are working ondiscussion, best practicesCoding dojo - we can work together on 4clojure problems or similarInvite Pavel Tisnovsky to Brno Clojure meetupI’m really looking forward to the next Brno Clojure meetup.I’d be love to see more people there as well.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>